{"_id": "a4b6623a", "question": "What are the leading risk factors for having a stroke?", "answers": "If you can answer this in a Quora answer, I’d say you deserve the Nobel’s Prize in Medicine!\nIn some cases, it’s obvious what caused a stroke: if somebody’s obese, has really high blood pressure, is really old, etc., it’s pretty clear-cut.\nBut I was 115 pounds, 90/60, and 24 years old when I had my stroke. My doctors looked at me, referred me to a cardiologist for another test, which was negative, and told me to go on my way. “The chance of you having a subsequent stroke is very small,” they assured me.\nSix months later, I was back in the hospital with another one. =(\nAbout six months after THAT, I was able to peer out from beneath my lead jacket of fatigue and pick my head up enough to wonder WHY I’d had a second one. It’d be nice to figure it out, I wagered, to prevent a third one. At that point, I’d already decided that if I had another one, JUST LET ME DIE.\nMy speech therapist referred me to a neurologist at the big city hospital nearby. In retrospect, he was nuts, but he did decide to perform a test just to check for certain that the cardiologist I’d originally seen hadn’t missed anything. (The first test, a TEE — trans esophageal echocardiogram — checked for a hole in my heart by sticking a camera down my throat look to look at my heart. The second test, a TCD — transcranial doppler — shot minuscule bubbles into my arm via an IV and listened to my brain to see if any of them made it up there.) Lo and behold, it dinged! I had a hole in my heart that allowed bubbles/clots/etc to pass through a ventricle and into my brain.\nBut, a week later, the neurologist called and said he wasn’t sure that the hole was the cause of my stroked. He explained that doctors usually require both a hole and a hypercoagulable disease — i.e. you need a hole in your heart and a reason to have a clot. “Why the h*ll did you have me do this test, then?” I wanted to shout.\nTo make a long story short, I decided to go ahead and have surgery to close the hole. It’s not terribly risky, but it is heart surgery. I haven’t had another stroke in 12 years, I’ve had a very good neurologist tell me that clots sometimes form in the area right around the hole *just because*, I’ve had doctors tell me to get my head screwed on straight — everybody knows a hole isnt enough without a hypercoagulable disease … I’ve pretty much just given up having any chance of ever knowing what caused my strokes.\nSo please, figure it out! LOL"}
{"_id": "efe5bc44", "question": "Is there a genetic factor to strokes?", "answers": "Family members share genes, behaviors, lifestyles, and environments that can influence their health and their risk for disease. Stroke risk can be higher in some families than in others, and your chances of having a stroke can go up or down depending on your age, sex, and race or ethnicity.\nThe good news is you can take steps to prevent it.\nGenetics and Family History\nWhen members of a family pass traits from one generation to another through genes, that process is called heredity.\nGenetic factors likely play some role in high blood pressure, stroke, and other related conditions. Several genetic disorders can cause a stroke, including ssickle cell. People with a family history of stroke are also likely to share common environments and other potential factors that increase their risk.\nThe chances for stroke can increase even more when heredity combines with unhealthy lifestyle choices, such as smoking cigarettes and eating an unhealthy diet.\nFamily health history is a record of the diseases and health conditions that happen in your family. Family health history is a useful tool for understanding health risks and preventing health problems."}
{"_id": "2d020f38", "question": "What factors make it likely to recover from stroke induced paralysis?", "answers": "I had a massive stroke in 2001 and lost all use of my right side my speech, and my right eye. Thankfully, I was young, 27, and I was told that would help in my recovery. It took almost 3 years of PT and occupational therapy to heal and recover almost all of my function. The brain does learn to find new pathways to send signals out to the body. It takes time. Lots of time.\nAs someone who had a stroke, I would like to tell you that your friends recovery can be frustrating for both of you.. She will need encouragement and yes, you'll have days where you have to push her harder than others and it will seem as if she is backsliding. Other days will be better for her. The best thing I can recommend, is to try to help her find as much humor in as many situations as you can. I've learned through many medical crises that laughter really does help your body to heal. It is better to laugh than to cry. Good luck."}
{"_id": "567e3c20", "question": "How is bore and stroke in an engine fixed? Based on what factors are they calculated? Is it power?", "answers": "The most basic parameters usually given for a reciprocating IC engine are Speed(rpm), Power, Brake Specific Fuel Consumption, Thermal Efficiency, Maximum Space available etc. Out of which we chose a compression ratio, maximum permissible temperature and calculate other cycle parameters from say Otto-cycle. From the P-V diagram, you can calculate the fuel air ratio required and the volume. This gives the sizing of the cylinder bore and stroke for an obtained volume. There is a lot of assumptions though, in absence of data it is ok to assume possible values to get a first cut idea."}
{"_id": "106309e9", "question": "What are bore value and stroke value? On what factor do they depend and how do they affect a bike's performance?", "answers": "Bore is the diameter of the piston\nStroke is the length which it sweeps up and down\nFor a given engine if displacement is kept constant, increased bore means reduced stroke and vice versa.\nHere are the things that get affected by a longer stroke :\nLonger stroke obviously needs a taller engine, since the crank and cylinder have to be equally tall.\nPeak piston speeds are non linearly proportional to stroke length\nThis means that for longer stroke:\nInduction efficency increases across RPMs, thus torque is increased\nRod and pin stresses increase, because the peak acceleration is higher\nPiston carries more peak kinetic energy per stroke, so a heavier flywheel is necessary, and vibrations increase.\nPeak potential RPM gets reduced, as it gets closer to Pomeroy limits\nPiston crown is likely to see much more thermal stress, since the surface area is lessened\nCombustion chamber is more oblong, this affects combustion efficiency - it takes longer, since the flame front travels down from the spark plug\n\nIn general, for a given displacement, the longest stroke (upto certain limits) gives the maximum BMEP for any chosen RPM. The flip side is that it will also have a lower potential peak RPM, due to material stress on the rod/crank and combustion chamber geometry limitations."}
{"_id": "8c76561a", "question": "Is excess sugar consumption one of the factors in causing a brain stroke?", "answers": "…not necessarily. Brain strokes occur due to brain cell being deprived of oxygen caused by an irregularity of blood flow. This can arise from either a blockage in the form of a blood clot or a vesicular eruption in one of the brain layers.\nAny prolonged excess of sugar or salt will cause an imbalance to the brain’s physiology and therefore exhibit itself by or with an ‘abnormal’ behavior."}
{"_id": "94e31b64", "question": "If two bike engines have same number of cylinders and same bore and stroke length but have different power and torque characteristics, what are the possible factors responsible for the difference?", "answers": "Cam timing, valve design, manifold design, exhaust design, fuel and ignition mapping, compression ratio, these are the main factors that’ll determine the characteristics for about 90%."}
{"_id": "f92b12a6", "question": "What is the stroke risk factor as a possible side effect for Covid-19 vaccines?", "answers": "Well the overall risk in having any reaction against this vaccine is 11 in 1 million for any normal vaccine its 25 in a million so this vaccine is twice as safe as other vaccines.\nThe Stroke group spokes persons recommend that people with a stroke problem should take the vaccine and is passed as been safe. Though if you are taking any anticoagulation medicine they should speak to their doctor first. Though there is in a lot of cases a doctor available at the vaccine centres who the vaccinator will ask if you show any doubts about taking the vaccine"}
{"_id": "d6256b02", "question": "What tests should I have, and how often, to monitor my risk factors for developing heart disease and stroke?", "answers": "Most cardiovascular diseases can be prevented by addressing behavioural risk factors such as tobacco use, unhealthy diet and obesity, physical inactivity and harmful use of alcohol using population-wide strategies.\nPeople with cardiovascular disease or who are at high cardiovascular risk (due to the presence of one or more risk factors such as hypertension, diabetes, hyperlipidaemia or already established disease) need early detection and management using counselling and medicines, as appropriate."}
{"_id": "f92781a8", "question": "Why does cholesterol increase the risk factor for heart disease and stroke?", "answers": "Cholesterol is a type of fat found in many foods that come from animals, such as meat and dairy products. Your liver also makes it. Your body needs some cholesterol, but too much can block your arteries. That's why adults with high cholesterol are more likely to have heart attacks and stroke. Several health conditions, your lifestyle, and your age and family history can increase your risk for heart disease. These are called risk factors. About half of all Americans (47%) have at least 1 of 3 key risk factors for heart disease: high blood pressure, high cholesterol, and smoking. Go to my Profile and you can find all about Heart Disease material there..."}
{"_id": "0faf7995", "question": "Is a long stroke the only factor to produce high torque in a engine? Then if petrol engines had a long connecting rod would they produce same torque as from a diesel engine of the same cc?", "answers": "Yes.\nTorque = Force X Distance (or Arm)\nForce is applied by the products of air-fuel combustion on the effective surface area of the piston and distance is determined by the geometry of the engine. Hypothetically, using petrol on a long stroke geometry will increase the torque, calorific value of petrol being marginally higher than that of diesel (and hence higher 'F').\nPractically, rate of combustion of petrol is higher than that of diesel. Consequently, combustion with petrol as fuel will not even be long enough to last a full length of stroke of the piston. This is what limits the length of stroke/ compression ratio of petrol engines in the first place. On the other hand, short stroke length in petrol engines allows them to attain higher rpms as compared to diesel engines, increasing the power output at higher rpms."}
{"_id": "a526cbfb", "question": "Hearts (organ): How does pulse compare to blood pressure as a risk factor for stroke?", "answers": "It is known that high blood pressure is a risk factor for stroke (brain).\nYou should keep your blood levels around 120/80 mmHg.\nHypertension is diagnosed when someone has pressure 140/90 or more. If lifestyle does not help to lower it, one should try with medications.\nPulse is not precise stroke predictor. We know that higher pulse on long term can be harmful for heart muscle cause it can cause tachycardia induced cardiomyopathy. It is recommended to keep it less than 75."}
{"_id": "8d277d00", "question": "Which factor causes the first stroke of engine?", "answers": "?????\nA valve opens to admit air & fuel into a cylinder as a piston goes down. The valve closes & piston rises to compress the mixture. As piston travels to top of cylinder, a spark is triggered, causing an explosion, pushing piston down. Another valve opens & piston rises, pushing spent mixture out. Cycle repeats."}
{"_id": "f9959225", "question": "Is it definitely the case that the aim should be to lower LDL cholesterol as it is a risk factor for strokes?", "answers": "Is LDL a risk factor for strokes? Saturated fat is associated with a reduced risk of strokes, and is generally believed to increase LDL, and higher LDL is associated with lower mortality in the elderly - which is when most stroke deaths occur.\nLDL can be a risk factor for atherosclerotic and thrombotic cardiovascular disease in general, but is not a very strong one, and it seems to be protective for ischaemic stroke..\nThe reason for this is likely that the LDL count can be raised by divergent processes, some of which are harmful, some of which are not. LDL can participate in reverse cholesterol transport, and elevated levels in this state are less likely to be harmful than the same levels (or even much lower levels) in a state of lipid accumulation due to excess insulin (hyperinsulinaemia).\nThis is why the TG/HDL ratio, the HDL level, the non-HDL/HDL ratio, and the HOMA-IR test of insulin sensitivity are all considered more reliable predictors of CVD than LDL cholesterol - they give some idea of where any excess cholesterol on LDL is headed. For example, statins lower LDL but are not beneficial, and may even be harmful, in people who already have a high HDL level and high reverse cholesterol transport activity.\nFruits and vegetables are also protective for stroke, probably due to helping prevent deficiencies of vitamins and minerals and supplying some extra antioxidants.\nCan dietary saturated fat be beneficial in prevention of\nstroke\nrisk? A meta-analysis."}
{"_id": "45f217dd", "question": "How does the orientation factor affect two-stroke and four-stroke engines?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "7e1ed93c", "question": "What factors contribute to the ratio of gas/oil in 2 stroke engines? Is it oil quality or engine quality?", "answers": "Only small engines still use premix today, the ratio is largely made to cover the worst case load and highest temperature the engine may see. Generally it is assumed that basic 2 stroke oil will be used.\nIn the late ‘60s, Japanese motorcycles started to introduce oil injection pumps that mixed the ratio based on speed and throttle opening, so the ratio varied considerably. That saved oil and also lessened fouling the spark plugs from low speed running. All the large 2 stroke outboards adopted similar oil injection systems, but now Evinrude is the last maker of large 2 stroke outboards. Their system lets you tell it what quality oil you are using and adjusts the ratio to suit.\nSo to generalize, the load and temperature mostly determines the oil needed, and to a lesser extent so does the oil quality. At the lightest loads the ratio on the old motorcycles may drop to less than 200:1. Premix is often done at 50:1. A modern Evinrude set to use the better synthetic oil probably idles at < 200:1, that is my guess.\nIdling 2 stroke dirt bikes that ran premix often fouled the spark plug and were hard to start, the switch to cleaner burning oil as well as oil injection helped a lot. Many 2 strokes today have a moderate but steady load while running with minimal idling time. We also now have stronger ignition systems in everything."}
{"_id": "55a2c9c8", "question": "What is an important factor for improving the efficiency of a 4-stroke engine?", "answers": "There are many types of efficiencies used to characterize the performance of an IC engine, like thermal efficiency, volumetric efficiency etc. However, fo the purpose of this question, I would consider the overall efficiency, that is the efficiency of converting energy from a unit mass of fuel into useful work done at the wheels.\nOverall efficiency depends on many factors and pointing out 1 single factor would not be of much use. So listing out a couple of high priority ones\nCompression ratio - Increasing CR improves the efficiency of engines.\nMixture control - Adjusting the ratio of air to fuel mass as per engine operating point.\nVolumetric efficiency - This denotes the ratio of volume actually available for combustion to the designed volume. Increasing VE improves the ability to extract more energy from fuel combustion.\nFor improving overall efficiency, there are quite a few techniques like\nValve timing - To contain the right amount of charge within the cylinder for optimum cylinder pressures, temperature and combustion stability.\nInjection/Spark timing - To optimize fuel plume temperatures.\nVariable compression ratio - This includes a cam operated mechanism to change the effective stroke of the piston, there by varying the compression ratio depending on engine operating point.\nHCCI - Homogeneous Charge Compression Ignition engines. This is by far the most fascinating and relatively new technology to improve efficiency. Here, we combine the advantages of\nhomogeneous mixtures like in gasoline engines to improve emissions, flame and combustion control etc.\ncompression ignition like in diesel engines to increase compression ratio and overall efficiency of engine.\nThis is not by any means an exhaustive list.\nHope this helps."}
{"_id": "bf0b839d", "question": "What are controllable risk factors for strokes?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "6cd93454", "question": "Is vitamin D3 deficiency a risk factor for stroke?", "answers": "Absolutely yes.\nVitamin D is not really a vitamin. Instead, it is a hormone that is needed to activate 1,000 human genes that regulate everything from the immune system to cancer prevention.\nOne critical factor that vitamin D regulates is levels of inflammation in the body. It is now well established that high cholesterol (one of the fats in the blood ) is not the sole factor in causing clogged arteries (atherosclerosis) and resulting heart attacks and strokes. A necessary piece in the development of plaques in artery walls that clog them is longstanding inflammation in the artery walls. We now know that people with low levels of vitamin D have very high levels of inflammation in the body and are at high risk for clogged arteries. One study looked carefully at people with very severe atherosclerosis (clogged arteries) and found that 71% of them had such low vitamin D levels that they were unmeasurable on lab tests. (see reference 1 below) A large number of strokes are caused by clogged arteries in the important arteries in the neck that feed blood to the brain.\nSeveral studies clearly demonstrate that adequate blood levels of vitamin D are protective against strokes. Those with the highest blood levels have far fewer strokes than those with low levels. (see reference 2 below)\nOne study evaluating the link between low vitamin D concluded that “Low levels of 25(OH)D (the blood measure of vitamin D) independently predicts fatal strokes, suggesting that vitamin D supplementation is a promising approach in the prevention of strokes.” (see reference 3 below)\nA Japanese researcher found that among elderly with low bone density (a common problem with low blood levels of vitamin D in the elderly) had a much higher frequency of stroke, suggesting that they had the same cause ie low vitamin D. (see reference 4 below)\nJ Gen Intern Med2002; 17:663\nArch Intern Med 2008; 168:1340\nStroke 2008; 39:2611\nStroke 2009; 40:e36"}
{"_id": "d130c5c5", "question": "Is it fatty food enough convincing risk factor for cardiovascular disease and stroke?", "answers": "Fatty food is one of the root causes of all heath hazards primarily affecting our cardiac health.. In general there are many risk factors for cardiac health problems including stroke. So yes it is a risk factor but not the only one. There are many factors which combinedly result in it. Some of them on which I can put reflection are sedentary life style, genes of ur father n forefathers, some metabolic effects etc.."}
{"_id": "076c227c", "question": "Which factor will affect if I stop one cylinder in four cylinder four stroke diesel engine rather than efficiency?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "2c6e4522", "question": "How do the risk factors for heart attack and stroke affect you? What can you do to live healthier?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "f4d00c9a", "question": "What are predisposing factors to stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "18acb4d4", "question": "Which factors lead up to Charles Dickens's stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "e0273ed2", "question": "What are the risk factors for carotid disease and stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "a6352b11", "question": "Are 90s two-stroke smokers (i.e., Honda NSR250, Aprilia RS250, Suzuki RGV250) really worth the hype or is the high price tag merely due to their nostalgia factor?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "bd527db6", "question": "What other risk factors are there for stroke other than smoking, drinking, and obesity?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "ebe6d233", "question": "What's the drag factor and stroke rate usually used by lightweight college rowers during a 2K/6K? I know it's relative for everyone, but what about on average?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "9a65141a", "question": "What risk factor led to Luke Perry's stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "ef736ba9", "question": "What is the environment factor and agent factor of stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "c0ed4e3b", "question": "What are stroke symptoms, causes, risk factors, and diagnosis?", "answers": "There are two fundamental driver of stroke: a hindered vein (ischemic stroke) or spilling or blasting of a vein (hemorrhagic stroke). A few group may have just a brief interruption of blood stream to the cerebrum, known as a transient ischemic assault (TIA), that doesn't cause enduring indications."}
{"_id": "b270de6b", "question": "Are both high systolic and diastolic blood pressures risk factors for heart attack and stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "388cd70b", "question": "Are there any unique risk factors for a stroke in women?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "6cb36db4", "question": "What factors affect the learning of speech and mobility after a stroke for elderly people?", "answers": "The factors that are most important are the specifics of the stroke, the timing, quality, and quantity of treatment, and the personal resilience of the individual.\nThere are many variables that determine an individual’s involvement after a stroke. Strokes can be ischemic or hemorrhagic, and the type of stroke is a predictor of damage to a certain degree. The site of the stroke is also a big determiner in the types and degree of involvement for communication and mobility.\nAfter a stroke, the availability of intense, high quality therapies are predictors in the best possible outcomes for the individual. Ideally, the best therapies are provided by a dedicated team who provide a thorough assessment and create a therapy plan that provides a sequenced multidisciplinary approach to the patient’s needs. Unfortunately, many facilities no longer offer a static team for patients and instead use lots of PRN staffing. While it’s therapy, it doesn’t always follow the scope and sequence as closely as a single provider can. This extends the length of treatment, especially in the area of communication and cognition.\nFinally, So many things change in an instant when you have a stroke: your independence, health, ability to care for yourself, livelihood, and relationships all fall under a cloud of doubt. The simple pleasures of life like enjoying a good meal with family or friends may be interrupted. The people who weather the inevitable depression that limits progress are usually those with the highest levels of personal resilience. These are the people who roll with the punches and revel in their small victories. They are the ones who give their all to their therapies on good and bad days. These are the ones who against the odds go home and figure out how to live their lives in a sea of change."}
{"_id": "467be228", "question": "What is the typical ratio between the number of chew strokes, and swallowing during normal mastication? What factors influence this ratio?", "answers": "Thanks for the A2A Greg.\nI don’t think that there is a definite set ratio. It varies from person to person.\nAnd this is also different in adult Vs children.\nSwallowing is a well documented process in dental literature.\nThere are significant factors that will influence chew strokes. Let's list a few:\nConsistency of food—ice cream Vs steak, for example.\nNumber of teeth present—generally, the more teeth, more efficient the chewing.\nPresence of aberrations in occlusion (how upper and lower teeth come together)\nFacial skeleton framework and muscles of mastication.\nMicroanatomy of individual teeth. Once the food is ready for swallowing (turned into a bolus)the process starts.Swallowing - Wikipedia"}
{"_id": "eec56850", "question": "Why are non-citizens in the U.S. undertreated for heart attack and stroke risk factors?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "e271135f", "question": "If efficiency is one of the important governing factors in engines, why are 2-stroke engines less efficient but powerful?", "answers": "Efficiency is a loose term that is used but when it comes to work you have to look at how the power is applied properly. A chainsaw for instance for a weed eater operates by moving its cutting edge very fast at high speed. Where is if you're pulling a load you need a low steady amount of toward at a load of middle-range RPM ran through different gear ratios to pull a heavy load.\nA chainsaw main only be three horsepower but it makes that power rating at 10,000 RPM, whereas your standard push mower maybe a 324 horsepower engine but makes it steady at 3600 RPM, balaban thing is that newer gas engines are not being rated in horsepower as they used to be videos of the manufacturers are going to series of engines that have a specific amount of torque. If I read the specifications right the newer engines r rating the power output by the torque at 1900 RPM versus the horsepower at 3600 RPM. And considering that people have been looking at 10 horsepower 11 horsepower 12 horsepower engines for the last hundred years for small engines whatever the horsepower rating and then they decide to change the rating system on the engines oh, and its memory serves it was because somebody sued one of the engine manufacturers and complained that his intention wasn't making for horsepower at 3600 RPM for whatever reason only been making 3.95 horsepower and that person won a lot of money in a lawsuit so now they change their power ratings at least that's the story that I got and I'm pretty much going to agree with that until I hear different. If you've ever watched race cars you can go to a drag race watch a 3000 pound car or a 2500 pound car race to get to five or six or seven second quarter mile elapsed times, then if you go to Indianapolis race car you will see a 1500 pound car making 1500 horsepower pushing that car at a breakneck speed for a long. Of time. If you ever watched a top fuel drag race dosage basically are using liquid Dynamite is called nitromethane race fuel with a little bit of ethanol added and it could create enormous amounts of power but you're literally feeding a 500 cubic inch engine with two spark plugs that have enough power to Arc weld metal cylinder gallons of fuel over a 3 to 4 second run down a quarter-mile track call me the last information I knew top fuel dragster consumed between 22 and 25 gallons 90% + nitromethane and makes in excess of ten thousand horsepower oh, and gets rebuilt almost every round if not every round and can explode in a pass. and if you ever saw the fuel injection system on these things it's literally squirting a stream of fuel into the intake system in only the air being forced in by the blower in the turbulence inside the engine literally breaking up the fuel, where is other cars use carburetor or fuel injection to atomiz it."}
{"_id": "6380db24", "question": "How does BDNF (brain-derived neurotrophic factor) help enhance the survival of neurons that have suffered from ischemic stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "83ffe4f6", "question": "Which heart problem has been identified as a known risk factor for stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "b0438dae", "question": "Does having a strong heart and a low pulse from cardio exercise reduce the likelihood of heart disease and stroke even if other risk factors are present?", "answers": "Does having a strong heart and a low pulse from cardio exercise reduce the likelihood of heart disease and stroke even if other risk factors are present?\nStudies determine risk and protective factors based on statistical results from populations, not individuals. I could probably dig up studies which would affirm the contention in your question, but these results would not necessarily be indicative your personal risks.\nSince your reason for asking this question is probably rooted in curiosity and/or concern about your own health, you should have a discussion about this with a doctor who can evaluate the protective effects of exercise in the context of your personal and family medical histories."}
{"_id": "36d3b461", "question": "What percentage of the reduction in CHD/stroke is due to statins, compared to that due to smoking or other factors ?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "88d3ac8a", "question": "What is the effect of smoking on hypertension? Can it be taken as a direct risk factor for hemorrhagic stroke?", "answers": "Smoking over a period of time directly causes hypertension as proven by multiple studies over decades. Nicotine disturbs the autoregulatory balance of the delicate autonomic nervous system. Over 5000 other chemicals work adversely in umpteen ways in the lungs, blood vessels, kidneys and more.\nThe link between smoking and stroke is mainly due to the atherosclerotic plaques that block the smallest vessels feeding the brain tissue. Haemorrhagic stoke indicates injured plaques after several attempt to autoregulate the flow of blood to the delicate tissue like brain.\nConsider lifestyle coaching to make wise choices for health and wellness life-long."}
{"_id": "236c288c", "question": "Could a daily dull headache in someone with all of the risk factors (obesity, high blood sugar, angina, age 50 years old) be a sign of a possible upcoming stroke?", "answers": "It could be many things … but most likely, it is a “Canary in the mine” telling you that you have “cheesed up [hardened] your arteries” and the heart is working harder to pump blood without the peristaltic elasticity in the blood vessels. The effect on the heart is it has to pump with higher pressure without any (or little) help from the arteries. The dull headache from this increased blood pressure is the number one cause. Number two would be from the high sugar and KetoAcidosis that goes with it. Number three would be that the arteries are starving the area they are supposed to serve of their blood supply and those areas are complaining about it.\nIf the pills can no longer squeeze more insulin out of the pancreas … then you need to supply an exogenous source (insulin shots) to control your blood sugar. It will not reshape the damage to the blood vessels that has already happened … but it will lesson future damage (slow it down)."}
{"_id": "061991c0", "question": "How many times will the BHP of an engine increase or decrease if the diameter of the piston increased by 20% and the stroke length is decreased by 20%, with all other factors remaining the same? Can you show your complete calculation?", "answers": "The BHP of any engine relies upon achieving overall harmony in the combination of a wide array of codependent factors. Harmony in this context implies that scaling any one of these factors - displacement being only 1 - while one or more of the remainder are held constant - may disrupt the success of the entire combination, and thus not be reflected in a correspondingly proportional increase in overall output. As a consequence, it is not possible to predict with any degree of accuracy the BHP effect of any engine simply by somehow plugging into some algorithm the changes you have specified. Of course, the effect upon displacement can be easily calculated (original cylinder area scaled up by 44% x stroke reduced to 80%) = 15.2% increase in displacement. Will this result in a 15.2% increase in BHP? Possibly, but by no means definitely. The increase in displacement is achieved while shortening the stroke, which will result in a lower peak piston speed for a given RPM. While this bodes well for parasitic losses like friction between the piston rings and cylinder walls, and reduced losses due to reduced effects of inertia, the shorter stroke will at the same time reduce the torque produced at a specific RPM as compared with the longer initial stroke length. Additionally, the RPM at which your engine will achieve its peak torque output will increase. While engine designers can make predictions as to how such variables will play off against one another with regard to change in BHP - actual determination is almost certainly a matter for an engine dyno. Unless the increased displacement of your modified engine is supported by a corresponding overcapacity of your carburetor/intake manifold and intake valves ( or fuel injection system) and the flow capability of your intake and exhaust valves, cylinder head passages and exhaust piping system the increased displacement might not produce a proportional - or indeed any increase in BHP at all. If any one of these or other factors is already limiting your BHP, it is conceivable that increasing displacement may have little or no positive effect."}
{"_id": "645363f1", "question": "Can type B blood clotting factor lead to strokes and heart attacks more so than other blood types?", "answers": "Blood types are due to antigens on the red blood cell. Clotting factors and blood type may have a correlation. Type AB, for example, display increased levels of a clotting factor called von Willebrand factor. This increased concentration is associated with a higher propensity to clot. It seems that the same propensity is seen in type A and B blood. Type O blood shows less propensity while type AB shows the most."}
{"_id": "cc9538d8", "question": "My grandfather has been in the ICU for 5 days now after a stroke. He is awake but he does not react to any stimuli. When will he be able to react to the external factors?", "answers": "Hearing is the last sense to go. So go and talk to him, play his favorite music. He may not respond but he’ll hear. Tell him everything that you want him to know. Don’t wait."}
{"_id": "cd6a827e", "question": "What is the single most important modifiable risk factor for stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "155ca5d7", "question": "Where can I find public data related to the risk factors of stroke?", "answers": "Here is one:\nHealthcare Dataset\nStroke\nData\n….data.gov.in\nhas aggregate data…you can go there and search for “stroke\""}
{"_id": "4cc336c1", "question": "Is it normal for a cat to be shedding all throughout the year? He’s an outside cat so I rarely see him, but when I do, I’m amazed on how much fur comes off him after each stroke. I wouldn’t say age is a factor as he’s been like this since a kitten", "answers": "Animals don't really stop shedding…they just have periods were they shed more than usual. Some individuals and breeds may shed more than others as well. We have a joke about German shepherds (shedders). They only shed twice a year, 6 months at a time.\nI'd only be concerned if you start noticing bald patches. That's a sign of something medical going wrong."}
{"_id": "bf1bd992", "question": "How do I find the balance factor percentage to balance a 50cc 2-stroke RC aeroplane engine?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "78960f5a", "question": "What are the factors that influence a return to work after a stroke? Do any regional differences exist?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "8a60ffdc", "question": "Which risk factor for stroke is uncontrollable?", "answers": "Stroke is the sudden loss of neurological function caused by a temporary or permanent cut of the blood supply to any part of the brain that lasts longer than 24 hours.\nIt is also called cerebrovascular accident (CVA). CVA is the 4th leading cause of death and the leading cause of disability. A stroke results in hemiplegia (paralysis of one side of the body).\nUncontrollable or non-modifiable risk factor of stroke are:\nAGE: The incidence of stroke increases with age.\nRACE: African Americans have more risk for stroke than Caucasians.\nSEX: The incidence of stroke is higher in men than in women.\nHEREDITY: Stroke is not hereditary. If a close family member has had a stroke, some of the risk factors may be hereditary, such as high blood pressure, diabetes, or abnormally high cholesterol.\nPREVIOUS HISTORY OF TIA (TRANSIENT ISCHEMIC ATTACK): You are at higher risk for having a second stroke after you have already had a small attack or TIA.\nFor further study on risk factor of stroke - \"Risk Factor Of\nStroke\n\" 7 Gigantic Influences - PHYLTH"}
{"_id": "be82f8c1", "question": "Can Celecoxib increase the risk of fatal heart attack or stroke even if you don't have any risk factors?", "answers": "I am not a doctor and if you have any concerns about medication prescribed to you, or if you are experiencing side effects, you should consult your doctor.\nHaving said that, I looked up the drug on the NICE website: BNF is only available in the UK\n- the National Institute for Health & Care Excellence. They determine which drugs can be prescribed in the UK, so a reliable source for me - but do feel free to look it up on your country’s official website for drugs.\nThis said that Celecoxib is one of a group of NSAIDs - Non Steroidal Anti Inflammatory Drugs. This group includes aspirin and other painkillers such as ibuprofen. Until recently, low-dose aspirin was prescribed for people at risk of stroke or heart attack. So by that logic, if anything, it should lower someone’s risk of heart attack or stroke.\nHaving read the info, I personally wouldn’t be worried about taking it."}
{"_id": "b8ab3b3b", "question": "Which is a modifiable risk factor for transient ischemic attacks and ischemi strokes?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "3f34478f", "question": "What is the most important independent cardiac risk factor for stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "023bf11f", "question": "Is a brain concussion a risk factor for stroke in 2 months to 10 years or even for life long?", "answers": "“Concussion” has no proper medical meaning. Some think concussion means any direct or indirect trauma to the head, others think that concussion requires transient loss of consciousness. It is not possible to test the question whether or not someone has suffered concussion. Therefore it has no scientific meaning.\n“Traumatic brain injury” is defined and has a scientific meaning. It is not a risk factor for stroke.\nInjury to the neck can damage the carotid or vertebral arteries causing arterial dissection and stroke: usually within a few day of injury.\nThe definition of stroke typically excludes traumatic brain injury."}
{"_id": "2132628d", "question": "Do you think the Drake Equation misses other significant limiting factors (complex cells, land, oxygen-rich, mastery of fire, language, tools, and mathematics, etc.) and through broad strokes grossly overestimates the final number?", "answers": "It's important to realise that there’s no estimate here to assess the accuracy of.\nThe Drake equation is a simple framework for considering factors that limit the number of actively-transmitting civilisations in our galaxy. Some of these factors are well-constrained by observation and others are not. By considering different possible constraints you can predict wildly different civilisation counts. So, no prediction.\nIn other words, it's perfectly possible that the resolution to the Fermi paradox lies within the framework provided by the Drake equation. One of the terms Drake describes may strongly limit the density of transmitting civilisations below detectable levels.\nNevertheless I think it’s fair to characterise this framework as being very coarse-grained. Given what I've said above this may seem irrelevant, but it is still worth breaking terms like ‘probability of life emerging on a well-situated planet’ down in my opinion since the whole point of the equation is to try and identify the limiting steps.\nI have a theory that\nthe emergence of simple life may be fairly common on such planets, while the move to multicellular life is prohibitively uncommon (there's some evidence for this in the fossil record).\nThe emergence of higher-order intelligence is inevitable in multi-cellular life and fairly rapid, given enough time, but the emergence of basic civilisation is not.\nTo elaborate, I think it likely that intelligence arose independently a number of times; certainly creatures such as dolphins and certain apes have developed complex behaviour, and perhaps long ago big-brained dinosaurs may have hunted in packs and communicated. Meanwhile, anatomically modern humans seemed to emerge, learn basic tool use, and then make no substantial progress for tens — hundreds! — of thousands of years. Perhaps it's this key step at which dumb luck comes in?\nAfter achieving civilisation it didn't take much time, really, to reach the ability to send interstellar communications. At no stage did civilisation collapse completely. Low-tech civilisation appears to be resilient (nuclear armed civilisation may not be of course…).\nNonetheless, these omissions from the Drake equation aren't critical since the existing terms fully encompass these issues; it's just that they are bundled up with other factors. I think it's interesting if, say, the small size of one of the equation's elements is down to a more specific issue (especially if some of the more specific items can be constrained empirically), but the equation is still a useful framework for discussion of the Fermi paradox."}
{"_id": "d63ad521", "question": "I have Factor V Leiden, chronic migraines, and a family history of strokes, should I be concerned, and if so, what should I do or ask my neurologist about?", "answers": "Just from the fact that you’re asking makes me think you’re at least a bit concerned. Explain your concerns to your neurologist and they’ll either put your concerns to rest or discuss how your risk factors play together and help you manage your health proactively with preventative measures"}
{"_id": "55d8450a", "question": "What factors determine the survival rate of massive stroke victims?", "answers": "There are well-know stroke risk factors (like high blood pressure, atherosclerosis, etc.) but there are not well-known stroke survival factors. Here are a few that come to mind though:\nThe speed of treatment - time is brain!\nThe location of the stroke. How severe is the bleeding or the clot? How much bloodflow is blocked?\nThe size of the stroke. How massive is the stroke?\nThe quality of treatment available - if surgery is required, how quickly can it be done?\nThe attitude of the person - are they a fighter?"}
{"_id": "a527a348", "question": "What factors affect stroke volume?", "answers": ""}
